Deserted Island Survival
Days
July 19: Set out
July 20-August 3: Special test
August 4-10: Cruise (free time)
August 11: Return, activity ends
Cards
All students will receive one of the following
eight kinds of cards at random.
Cards can only be traded to students of the same year
in different classes. (No trade-backs allowed)
Basic Cards
Lead-off: Holder may use 50% more points at the start of the test.
Supplement: Doubles private points earned by the holder.
Halve: Halves private point penalties inflicted on the holder.
Bandwagon: Holder designates a group at the start of the test.
Half of private point rewards earned by that group...
Insurance: Gives holder a single day to recover in case of ill health
that would otherwise force a drop-out.
Special Cards
Reinforcement: Holder can exist as the seventh person in a group.
Male/female ratio...
Negate: Holder pays no private points when paying a penalty.
Trial: Holder may increase class points awarded by 50%. However...
What makes this different from
last year's version is the scale.
In addition to the testing
period being longer,
the island we'll be
using is bigger, as well.
And as all class years
will be competing at once,
the number of opponents will be
the greatest in school history.
I can't reveal all the rules at
this particular moment in time,
but in the upcoming special test,
you'll be able to form large
groups of up to six to cooperate.
These large groups will
be based on small groups.
*The class points earned by the top three groups will be
transferred from the years of the bottom three groups.
*Class points will be split equally between classes in the group,
regardless of number of members. (Rounded)
Rules
-Group composition: Groups of up to three people
(*up to four for first-years) must be formed by 7/16.
-Classes and members: Small groups must be of students from the same year,
but not necessarily the same class.
-Male-Female ratio: If a group is mixed-gender,
at least 2/3 of the group must be girls.
-Large group formation: After the special test begins,
large groups of up to six people can be formed.
-Large group conditions: Large groups consisting of four or more
people must contain at least 50% girls.
- Drop-outs and penalties: If all members of a group are unable to continue the test
and drop out, they will fail the test and receive a penalty.
Think carefully about what
kind of group you want to form.
Classroom of the Elite 4th Season 2nd Year 1st Term
What did you want to talk
to me about, Koenji?
#6 A Tumultuous Scramble
I believe you've neglected
a crucial point, Teacher.
A crucial point?
If a student decides to take
the special test alone,
and they're not feeling well that day...
What happens then?
A ridiculous question.
Last year, you dropped out due to illness.
But this year, there will
be no special treatment.
Your penalty will be to
pay six million points.
You don't have enough to pay that.
What will you do?
Prioritize your freedom and be expelled?
I suppose we'll find out.
You're free to go now, Teacher.
By the way...
Do you have business with
me, Ayanokoji, my boy?
You seem to excel at hiding things.
But from you, I cannot ascertain
what is truth and what is lies.
I do not trust the words
of a person like that.
You don't seem like the kind
of person to trust anyone.
True enough.
So, how are you going to
approach the upcoming test?
A fine question.
There's no harm in asking—
will you allow me to join your group?
I'm afraid not.
There's too much on the
line to involve someone
who's sure to drop out on the first day.
I see. I cannot object to that.
Are you sure you can
afford to think that way?
I'll think very carefully about how
to surmount this until the day comes.
Deserted Island Survival Test Notes.PDF
Rules
-Group composition: Groups of up to three people
(*up to four for first-years) must be formed by 7/16.
-Classes and members: Small groups must be
of students from the same year,
but not necessarily the same class.
-Male-Female ratio: If a group is mixed-gender,
at least 2/3 of the group must be girls.
-Large group formation:
After the special test begins,
large groups of up to six people can be formed.
-Large group conditions:
Large groups consisting of four or more
people must contain at least 50% girls.
- Drop-outs and penalties: If all members of a group
are unable to continue the test
and drop out, they will
fail the test and receive a penalty.
Forming groups of the most
talented people in the year
to aim for the top spots
could mitigate risk,
but it won't change the
class point differentials.
Working within your class is high-risk
but lets you keep all the points,
so it's a chance to make
progress against them.
But what if the other classes
work together without us?
I wonder how Sakayanagi-san, Ryuen-kun,
and Ichinose-san will approach it.
Class A is so far ahead,
all they'll want is to keep
anyone from gaining on them.
So what about a three-class alliance?
Classes B through D could work
together to close the gap.
The enemy of the enemy
is my friend, you mean?
A reasonable idea.
But if we propose the idea
of isolating Class A,
Sakayanagi-san will likely retaliate.
It would be nice if one of the other
classes would make the offer instead.
It seems they've made their move already.
I've ordered the others not
to form groups just yet.
Have you heard from Ichinose?
I would expect her to propose a
full second-year collaboration.
Not at the moment.
If she wanted all the second-year
students working together,
I would expect her to be
putting feelers out already.
In this year's island survival game...
Would it be possible to ask
you to take first on your own?
Don't be ridiculous.
The only thing we know now is that it's
a special test on a deserted island.
I thought you might not even need a group.
If we can take first place,
we're guaranteed to gain
on the competition.
Then we can focus on group
formations to prevent expulsion.
Students in the bottom five groups will
be penalized with expulsion, after all.
We can't pay the points to save them all.
Yes.
We can't make point transfers
once the test has started,
so I'd like to get as many points
to the at-risk students as possible,
but if the students we lend points
to are hit with the penalty,
the consequences will be terrible.
They'll have to do what they
can to survive on their own.
Can I talk with you again sometime?
I'll do what I can.
That's all I ask.
Thank you.
Hey.
Hello there, Ayanokoji-kun!
This is an unusual pairing.
I have a bad feeling about this.
Can I just go home?
Ishizaki...
You didn't answer our text,
so we came to you.
Can we talk?
You want me...
to pair up with you?
Me, Albert, or Shiina...
Just work with someone from Class B!
In other words, you want
me to join Class B?
Yeah!
Is there some benefit to me in that?
It's not a bad deal for you at all, man.
If we make it to Class A,
we'll give you 20 million points
and welcome you into our class.
I want that, too!
Yes.
Is Ryuen behind this offer?
Or was this your idea, Ishizaki?
It was my idea!
Ryuen-san doesn't know about it.
Have you considered what
will happen if he finds out?
Of course not! I can't afford to!
That's part of going for it.
What matters in the special test is to
not lose any second-year class points.
In order to place in the top three,
we'll need you, Ayanokoji-kun.
I understand your proposal.
You'll work with us, then?!
I appreciate the offer,
but I can't agree at this stage.
How come?!
I think we need to offer
better conditions.
Besides, to place at the top
of the island survival game,
the best group would be Ryuen-kun,
Kaneda-kun, and Ayanokoji-kun together.
We need to get Ryuen-kun involved.
There's no way!
You really think Ryuen-san
would agree to my plan?
I doubt he'd be enthusiastic, no.
For now, let's be satisfied
that we were able to convey
our idea to Ayanokoji-kun.
Fine, I get it.
I don't know if I can
meet your expectations,
but I'll give it some thought.
Hey, Shinohara!
What do you want?
Um, you know...
Have you figured out who
you're partnering with yet?
No. Why do you ask?
O-Oh, no reason! Just figured I'd ask!
Oh, really?
You'll be with Sudo-kun and
Hondo-kun regardless, right?
What's wrong with that?!
I'll have more fun with those guys anyway!
Yes, I'm sure.
But while I'm sure those guys
could figure it out without me...
I'd be happy to lend you a
hand if you needed it, so...
If you need some help, y'know...
I'd be willing to group
up with you, y'know?
What's this all about?
You want to be in a group with me?
D-Don't get the wrong idea, okay?!
Look, you could actually get
expelled over this, right?!
So, as an expression of my kindness,
I'm willing to take the
hit and keep you safe!
What do you mean, "take the hit"?
I never asked you.
Good morning, Ike-kun!
Do you have a minute?
Yeah, I've got nothing better
to be doing right now!
Kobashi-san from Class C wants
to invite you to join her group.
Would you be willing
to discuss it with her?
You mean it?! Heck yeah,
I'm on my way right now!
But you were talking to Shinohara-san
just now, weren't you?
You really want to go?
It's fine by me.
He wouldn't stop blabbing at me,
and it was so annoying.
Take him wherever you want.
I'm the one who's annoyed right now!
C'mon, let's go!
I guess someone else needs me, huh?!
Satsuki.
Komiya-kun...
Ayanokoji-kun.
You're in deep trouble.
You actually drew the "Trial" card.
Eight types of cards
with special effects,
distributed to students for the test...
Trial:
You may increase your class points
awarded in the special test by 50%.
However, if not in the top 30% of groups,
your group will receive a penalty.
The extra points will be provided by the school.
In exchange for increasing our
class points earned by 50%,
you'll suffer a penalty if you
don't place in the top 30%.
I doubt anyone would trade for that card.
It looks like you'll have no choice
but to aim for a high placement.
I'm afraid I could also get rid of it
if I find someone who wants to trade.
It's up to you which you choose.
I just hope you can find someone
who wants it in the first place.
And just so you know,
I was being sarcastic.
I'll bet.
Punishment for what you
put me through every day.
I'm not trying to
"put you through" anything.
Hey, you—
You found a partner?!
Yeah. That a problem?
But I invited you just the other day!
And we're not supposed to partner
up until Horikita says so!
I don't need permission
for a handshake agreement.
Though I fully intend to
make it official today.
Who did you partner up with?!
Komiya-kun from Class B.
What?! Komiya?!
That playboy from the basketball team?!
He's not a playboy.
We're going to discuss it
at the café after class.
I'm so glad you're willing
to partner with me.
Thanks for asking!
What's the status?
It doesn't seem like the
worst case possible,
but he seems really depressed about it.
I'd like to avoid a situation
where Ike can't meet his
potential due to Shinohara.
What should we do?
He doesn't seem about to go off the rails,
so we can probably wait and watch for now.
Yeah.
I'd like to look more into Komiya's
motives for inviting Shinohara.
I'll think up who Ike-kun
can partner with instead.
Please do.
You don't seem too surprised.
Did you realize I was following you?
I just tend not to show my surprise.
What were you talking to Hirata-kun about?
Ike-kun? Because of the island test?
Is that any of your business?
Don't put up those defenses.
There's just something I figured I
should tell you ASAP, so I reached out.
What's that?
The Trial card is a tough one, huh?
If you have any trouble,
I'd be happy to help you out.
You think that the two of us
working together would give the
greatest chance of survival?
You could tell?
I thought if I didn't hurry,
you might get sold out.
I won't form my group until
the month is out, at least.
I'd like to see what other
classes are up to first.
Got it. So there's nothing
I can say at the moment.
Think about it, though.
Here. My personal contact info.
See ya!
Hey!
You ready to join us?
Sorry, but this is about something else.
You want my advice, then?
So you ran off to meet
with Ayanokoji-kun, huh?
Hey, Nishino! I told you not to tag along!
You two are close, huh? Weird pairing.
You aren't listening!
This is why no one likes you!
I've got everything I need.
And I'm curious as to why
you're meeting up in secret.
I wanted his advice about Komiya.
Komiya-kun?
I heard he wants to group up
with Shinohara from our class.
I want to know what kind of person he is.
He's just a good guy, y'know?
Athletic, too!
Are they going out?
I-I dunno how to answer that...
Ishizaki's the last person
to ask about romance.
And you're not?!
I'm better than you, at least.
They're not dating, but Komiya-kun has
a crush on Shinohara-san for sure.
What? For real?
I guess he did mention liking
a girl in another class...
But why are you worried about that?
Ike in our class has a crush on Shinohara.
Huh?
You really shouldn't get involved
in other people's love lives.
Normally, I wouldn't.
But I can't ignore it when
it concerns my class.
We need Ike at his best, after all.
Okay! I'll lend you a hand!
Ishizaki, are you serious?
You're, like, Komiya's best friend.
Still, I can't ignore Ayanokoji
when he needs help!
So, what should I do?
Let's see...
Komiya wants to tell Shinohara how
he feels while they're on the island.
Why not let him, then?
I was wondering what you
wanted to talk to me about...
but I don't see why this
is anyone's business.
I'm not sure.
Ike might slip up if he's distracted
by the Shinohara business.
You think he could end up
expelled due to heartbreak?
I can't say it's not a possibility.
That would be extremely foolish.
What if Ike-kun tells
her how he feels first?
Get the slate clear so
he can focus on the test.
Does it work like that?
Despite all the fields in which you excel,
you seem utterly hopeless
when it comes to love.
I'm learning a lot.
Very well.
You want me to guide Ike-kun and
Shinohara-san to end up together?
Yeah.
I'm afraid it might already be too late.
Advanced Nurturing High School Administration
Announcement of Island Survival Game
Group Formation
Class 2-B  Komiya Kyogo
Class 2-B  Kinoshita Minori
Class 2-D  Shinohara Satsuki
The listed members have formed a small group.
You're not going to pair
with anyone? How come?
Being by myself will
make me more flexible.
And taking first place by myself
will gain us 300 class points.
You seem so confident, I feel
like you might just do it...
If you take solo first place,
I might pass out from happiness!
You'd be so awesome!
I wish you'd partner with me...
and protect me, though.
There's a way to save you regardless.
Get enough private points to save you.
Well, sure, that's a possibility...
But even in a six-person group,
each person would need a million
points to prevent expulsion, right?
I don't have that much.
How many do you have now?
Um... 240,000 points.
I've been saving up pretty well lately!
760,000 to make up, then.
Even if I gave her my entire stock
of 250,000, she'd be 500,000 short.
Kei.
I'll get you the money.
S-Sure. Thanks.
The special test to have me expelled
lasts until the start of the second term.
The next test might be the final
battle for Tsukishiro and me.
If I grouped up with her and
got her involved in my baggage,
the consequences would be severe.
So, what did you want to talk to me about?
I'll be blunt.
At the rate you're going,
your class is unlikely
to return to Class B,
let alone reach Class A.
That is pretty blunt.
Unfortunately, that's not all.
It seems to me that it's only a matter
of time until you fall to Class D.
I understand why you feel that way.
But—
You're about to say
something abstract like,
"We'll fight our way through with
effort and friendship," right?
You won't be able to win like that.
I've seen no growth in
your class as a whole.
That's...
That's not true!
Everyone's definitely growing!
It's clear as day from your OAA.
Your class has unquestionably had the
slowest growth out of the four classes.
You've proven unable to show your full
potential in unfavorable circumstances.
People like Ryuen-kun and me
are able to bare our fangs even
when the odds are against us.
You stand no chance of
victory as you are now.
I think that's an uncontroversial
statement at this point.
You called me here to say that?
If I merely meant to chastise you,
I wouldn't waste both our time.
Will you work with me, Ichinose-san?
It's the only way you can
catch up with Class A.
I can't imagine what you'd get
out of a partnership with us.
True. You have little to offer us
in terms of competitive potential.
But you have a powerful weapon
that no other class has.
Trust, of course.
I am confident that you will not
betray me under any circumstances.
That is a crucial element
when taking a partner.
You may not be able to catch up to us,
but you can overtake Ryuen-kun's class
and put more distance
between you and Class D.
Shouldn't your priority right
now be to achieve stability?
Sakayanagi-san...
may I be honest with my opinion?
Of course.
I think you're just afraid of the other
three classes teaming up against you.
We could certainly sabotage
you if we all worked together.
If such an attempt were to succeed,
it would put you in a very
bad spot moving forward.
Am I wrong?
It seems I may have underestimated you.
If you agree to work with me,
I am willing to give you enough points
to prevent three people's expulsion.
As I know you do not wish
to see anyone expelled,
I'm sure you'll find
this a tempting offer.
What about five people's worth?
That would certainly let me rest easy.
How very greedy of you.
I expect to receive an amount
similar to that very soon,
so I'll make the payment just for you.
You have a deal.
Ryuen-kun and Horikita-san
are both fearsome opponents.
We're the ones who will take first place.
I'll do whatever it takes
to make that happen.